

📕 +44 7979304633 🗹 testandplayalltime@gmail.com 😭 London, UK in pulkit-gera

darthgera 123

Portfolio

Profile

Machine Learning Engineer specializing in neural rendering, generative models, and 3D vision. Experienced in photorealistic rendering, dynamic texture synthesis, and high-fidelity scene reconstruction. Developed real-time neural rendering for human avatars, optimized multi-GPU training, and designed relighting and environment-aware rendering frameworks. Previously worked on a wide variety of full-stack development and other projects, contributing to significant advancements in GenAI, AR/VR applications and achieving publications in renowned conferences.

Education

MS by Research, Computer Science

IIIT Hyderabad, India

CGPA: 10.0/10.0

2021-2022

Thesis: Casual Scene Capture and Editing for AR/VR Applications.

BTech, Computer Science

IIIT Hyderabad, India

CGPA: 8.77/10.0 2017-2021 Relevant Courses: Software Engineering, Data Structures, Operating Systems, Computer Vision, Computer Graphics,

Unix Tools and Scripting, Mobile Robotics & Statistical Methods in Al

Professional Experience

Applied Scientist Intern

London, UK

Flawless AI

11/2024 - present

- Designed a dynamic neural texture module for stable mouth interior generation, reducing inconsistencies in neural rendering and enhancing photorealism for film-grade dubbing..
- Developed a multi-GPU distributed training pipeline using PyTorch Fabric, integrating mixed precision training and gradient accumulation, leading to a $2\times$ reduction in training time and improved model convergence.
- Implemented a denoising module to remove stuck grain artifacts, reducing inference errors and cutting operational costs by through more efficient rendering.

Research Intern Saarbrücken, Germany

VCAI, Max Planck Institute for Informatics Advisor: Dr Christian Theobalt

10/2022 - 06/2024

- Formulated a novel framework based on 3D Gaussian Splatting that enables real-time photorealistic rendering of real humans from novel views under arbitrary input environment map illuminations.
- Setup and calibrated a specialized USC Lightstage consisting of 331 programmable lights and 40 RED Komodo cameras. Curated preprocessing pipelines for processing terabytes of captured data.
- Curated a novel dataset consisting of 70 human avatars under varying light patterns such as OLAT and spherical gradients.
- Curated synthetic datasets using RenderPeople assets under varying illumination using Blender and scripted using Python.

Research Intern

Quebec City, Canada

Université de Laval Advisor: Dr Jean François Lalonde

05/2021 - 10/2022

- Designed a novel NeRF-based representation for a causally captured full HDR radiance field of a large indoor scene without any elaborate setups or complex capture protocols.
- Predicts full HDR panoramas from any location of the scene and can synthesize correct lighting effects which enable augmentation of indoor scenes with synthetic objects.
- Funded by MITACS-Globalink. Presented at BMVC 2022 and OmniCV2022, CVPR-W.

Research Assistant

Hyderabad, India

06/2019 - 05/2022

CVIT, IIIT Hyderabad Advisor: Dr P.J. Narayanan

- Developed a novel neural rendering framework for simultaneous view synthesis and appearance editing of a scene with known environmental illumination captured using a mobile camera.
- Disentangled the appearance and learned an independent lighting representation which enables editing of the appearance of real scenes in interesting and non-trivial ways. Presented at ICVGIP 2021.

Deep Learning Intern

Remote(Bengaluru,India)

Segmind Solutions

08/2020 - 10/2020

- Ported various object detection and semantic segmentation algorithms into a single unified tensorflow library
- Abstracted framework reduced time for prototyping and increased ease of setup by reducing to 5 lines of code.

Technical Staff Remote(Geneva, Switzerland)

10/2019 - 02/2020 AlCrowd

- Designed over 200 machine learning challenges of different modalities such as tabular data, images, etc.
- Made benchmarks and tested different research-based challenges of different topics.

Computer Vision Intern

Hyderabad, India

DreamVu

06/2018 - 07/2018

• Designed image-processing tools to benchmark data captured by the PAL omnidirectional vision system.

Assisted in capturing data ind improving image quality captured by the camera system.

Publications

- Casual Indoor HDR Radiance Capture from Omnidirectional Images. Pulkit Gera, Mohammad Reza Karimi Dastjerdi, Charles Renaud, P. J. Narayanan, Jean-François Lalonde. British Machine Vision Conference 2022
- Neural view synthesis and appearance editing from unstructured images. Pulkit Gera, Aakash KT, Dhawal Srikonda, PJ Narayanan. ACM Indian Conference on Computer Vision, Graphics and Image Processing 2021

Skills

- Languages: Python, C++, Bash, Javascript, GO, Matlab, SQL, Ruby on Rails
- Frameworks: Pytorch, Tensorflow, Metashape, COLMAP, Mitsuba3, OpenGL, Langchain
- Technologies: Git, Meshlab, Blender, Docker, SLURM, Nuke

Projects

RAG Agents GenAl, Information Retrieval

Developed a Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) system leveraging LLMs with LangChain for backend processing and integrated with a Streamlit-based frontend to answer questions across various databases and modalities, including coffee orders, research papers, and image datasets.

UV-Relighting Computer Vision

Predict relit UV map based on input environment maps, involving mesh and UV map recovery for captured 3D subjects and employing techniques like latent vector conditioning and **diffusion-based relighting** to achieve accurate illumination under various conditions.

LANet Computer Vision

End-to-end trainable luminance attentive network with two streams for HDR reconstruction trained on Laval Indoor HDR dataset.

SLAM: Pose Graph Estimation

Computer Vision, Robotics

Computer Graphics

Developed and optimized a pose graph using SLAM to correct the robot's estimated path through non-linear weighted optimization techniques such as Levenberg-Marquardt.

Ray Tracing Computer Graphics

Ray Tracing engine built in C++ than can perform volume rendering and handle basic geometries

Airplane Simulator

3D aircraft simulator using OpenGL and C++, featuring a mini-world that includes an airplane, checkpoint islands, a volcano island, and enemy parachutes.

POSIX Shell Operating Systems

An implementation of the POSIX Shell from scratch in C using only system calls which supports functionality like piping and redirection along with a few new custom commands.

QuizApp Fullstack Development

Interactive quiz portal with a Go (Gin) backend and a React frontend, allowing administrators to create and manage various quiz types while providing users with a dynamic and engaging platform to participate in quizzes.

Multimodal Summarization of News Articles

NLP

Generate high-quality summarizations of news articles by taking text and image modalities and leveraging visio-linguistic transformers like OSCAR and UNITER.

Guess the name Information Retrieval

Created a crowdsourcing platform with a Flask frontend to fill gaps in Hindi Wikidata by connecting loosely related entities.

Additional Experience and Achievements

- Ranked 1841 in JEE Main 2017 out of approximately 1 million applicants.
- Winner of Megathon 2019, Big Data Track (India's Largest student organized hackathon).
- Dean's merit list awardee given to top 3% of the class.
- Finished 3rd in AlCrowd Blitz, out of 350+ teams.
- Student Placement Cell, IIIT Hyderabad
- Head Finance, E-Cell IIIT Hyderabad